Andrew McLane

southsiskiyoudigital@gmail.com (530)500-2898 Dunsmuir, CA

Summary

A self-taught developer with over 3 years of professional development expertise. My work experience includes developing compelling real world, enterprise augmented and virtual reality applications in Unity and native iOS, backend service integration, and custom graphics programming. I am outgoing, a team player, live to learn and teach, and always eager to build with the newest technologies.

Skill Highlights

Unity3D, Xcode, Unreal Engine, C#, Swift, C++, Objective-C, Metal, UML, ML Agents (AI), Narrative Gameplay, Prototyping, PostgresSQL, Writing Skills, Interactive Dialogue Systems (Ink), Teaching Experience, Agile Software Development, Regex, Git, Typescript, Node.js, React.js, HTML, CSS

Experience

Volunteer Gameplay Programmer

Icarus Alpha • Remote 10/2024 - Present

Program Animations and Narrative Logic in Unreal (C++) and Unity (C#)

Unity Developer

Gravity Jack • Spokane, WA (Remote)

12/2021 - 08/2024

- Developed custom AR/VR solutions for 11 customers including Meta, The Intrepid Museum of NY
- Enhanced company processes by having digested SOWs into UML diagram artifacts and proofread project proposals
- Advocated use of and taught ML Agents, Narrative Driven Software, Unity Unit Testing, DLLs, UI Toolkit (XML+CSS)

Unity Developer

Gamucatex • København (Remote)

08/2021 - 12/2021

- Developed and delivered the Alpha build of an historical-educational turn-based strategy card game in Unity in start-up-sized team
- Refined game logic, fixed bugs, and worked with art team to update sprites and UI

Education

Unity and Unreal

GameDevHQ 11/2021

- Completed *Professional Unity Developer Program Alumni* course, which includes Prototyping, 2D Development, VR/AR, Level Design & Rendering, Timeline & Cinemachine, Unity Input System, Physics, Logic & Interactions
- Completed *Unreal Engine: Foundations* course, which includes Unreal Engine Basics, Programming with Blueprints and C++, Character Systems, Environment Interactions, Basic NPC AI systems

German Studies

San Francisco State University • San Francisco, CA

· Graduated Magna Cum Laude